&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：有几个不同的
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: There are several different
你可以尝试从流的角度来模拟我所要求的，
ways that you could try to model what I asked for from a stream's perspective,
我尝试了几种不同的建模方法。
and I have attempted several different ways of modeling this.
因此，我将向您介绍一种建模方法
And so, I'm gonna walk you through one way of modeling it and
然后告诉你为什么这不是一个好主意，然后告诉你第二种方法，好吗？
then show you why that's not a good idea and then show you a second way, okay.
但这并不是唯一的方法。
But that's not at all the only ways to do it.
对此有不同的思考方式，其中一件事就是成为
There are different ways of thinking about it and one of the things about becoming
一个好的反应式编程开发人员应该了解所有
a good reactive programming developer is understanding all
您可以使用的工具来了解我们如何混合和
the tools that are available to you in understanding how we can mix and
匹配这些不同的更高级别的流操作以实现我们的目标。
match these different higher level stream operations to accomplish our goals.
老实说，这仍然是我正在积极学习的一条道路。
That is still a path that I am actively learning on, to be completely honest.
我不会以任何方式，形状或形式表明我是这方面的大师。
And I wouldn't in any way, shape or form suggest that I'm a master of that.
我仍然在尝试更好地学习如何在流中对这些类型的东西进行建模。
I am still trying to learn better how to model these sorts of things in streams.
因此，思考这个问题的一种方式是我们可以将点击看作单个
So, one way of thinking about this is we could think about the clicks as a single
数据流和作为第二个流行进的计时器。
stream of data and the timer that's marching as a second stream.
我们可以说，如果我把这两个流组合在一起，我会做什么。
And we could say what am I gonna do if I compose those two streams together.
所以，让我们开始吧，让我们看看它是如何工作的。
So, let's start that and let's see how that works.
让我们调用，让我们为我们的点击创建一个流。
Let's call let's make one stream for our clicks.
我在幻灯片中向你们展示了最简单的，
And I showed you in the slides that the simplest,
创建我们可以将数据推送到其中的空流的最简单方法是说.of。
easiest way to make an empty stream that we can push data into is to say .of.
让我们制作另一个计时器，因为计时器是ASQ.react.of。
And let's make another one for the timer is ASQ.react.of.
让我们看看这对我们来说是怎样的，看看是否
Let's just see how this works out for us and see whether or not
这就是我们想要走的路。
This is gonna be the path that we wanna go down.
所以每次我收到Click事件时，我都可以说Clicks.push和
So clicks, every time I get a click event, I could say clicks.push and
将事件推入管道末端，流的末端。
push an event into the end of the pipe, into the end of the stream.
然后，在外面我会收到那个事件，
And then, on the outside of it I'm gonna receive that event,
当然，这是一种方法。
of course, that's one way of doing that.
我可以给自己设定一个间隔，让自己每隔一段时间就跑一次
And I could set myself up an interval to run every
1000毫秒&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：以及
1000 milliseconds. &gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: And
我可以把它的定时器推下来。
I could push a timer of that down.
事实上，你可以说这是一个很常见的模式，我应该有一些
In fact, you could say that's such a common pattern I ought to have some little
用于将计时器事件向下推的适配器，对吗？
adapter for pushing timer events down, right?
所以，是的，我们可能想为我们自己创造一个小工具
So yeah, we might wanna create ourselves a little utility for
制作定时器流以将定时器事件向下推。
making a timer stream to push timer events down.
但是也许我们不会去推动任何事情，仅仅是有一个事实，那就是有一个事件
But maybe we're not going to push anything that just the fact that there's an event
没有数据可以推送，所以在称为点推送的过程中，这里没有事件。
that there's no data to push along so in that called dot push was no events here.
所以现在，我有两个不同的流，我可以考虑
So now, I have two different streams and I could think about
我有什么可能的方式将两个流合并成一个合成的第三个流。
what are my possible ways of merging two streams into a synthetic third stream.
嗯，我真正想要的是我想发送一个活动
Well, what I really want is I want to send an event out
只要这两件事都发生过一次。
whenever both of those things have happened once.
或者无论何时只要有一个事件准备好了，这两个都是我想要的
Or whenever there is an event ready with both of those that's when I want
我的合成事件将被激发，这将是我发出的消息。
my synthetic event to fire which is gonna be my messages that go out.
因此，您可以将其建模为与其在反应中称为Zip的方式相同
So, you could model this the same that by the way it's called Zip in the reacts
反应式扩展世界。
the reactive extensions world.
如果你喜欢这里，你可以使用.zip或者
You can used .zip if you like here or
我喜欢把它叫做dot all，因为它正在等待它们全部出现。
I like to call it dot all because it is waiting for all of them to show up.
因此，我们可以将其建模为ASQ.react.all和
So, we could model this is saying ASQ.react.all And
给它两个流，给它点击和定时器流。
give it both streams give it the clicks and the timer stream.
这将是我们称之为的新闻流，
And that's going to be a NEWS STREAM that we call,
我不知道我不会给它起个好名字所以
I don't know I'm not coming up with a good name for it so
我们就叫它准备好了，我准备打印出一条消息或者
let's just call it ready I'm ready to print out a message or
也许我就把它叫做消息流，好吧。
maybe I'll just call it the messages stream, okay.
这就是我的新消息流，并且
So that's my new messages stream, and
我可以说消息流将接收
I could say the messages stream is going to receive
每次队列中有来自这两个流的东西时都会发生事件。
an event every time there's something in the queue from both of these two streams.
那就是它将继续前进的时候。
That's when it's going to move on.
但是它将要打印出来的东西或者它将要继续的东西
But the thing that it's going to print out or the thing that it's going to move on
将是事件对象和
is going to be a combination of an event object and
一个未定义的值，因为我在这里不推送任何东西。
an undefined value because I don't push anything in here.
因此，我可以通过这样的方式订阅该流，即每次出现新事件时都会这样说。
So, I could subscribe to that stream by saying every time a new event comes in.
我知道我会在这里得到一些数据，但我实际上并不关心
I know I'm gonna get some data in here but I actually don't really care about
数据。&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：那么，
the data. &gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: So,
我知道每次合成消息时都会调用这个val函数
I know that this val function is gonna get called every time the message's synthetic
流有东西可以给我。
stream has something to give me.
我可以拿到$.list
And I could take $.list and
我可以在名单上加上一个部门
I could append to that list a Div,
上面写着点击
that says clicked for
举个例子好吗？
example, okay?
现在，如果你运行这个代码，
Now, if you ran this code,
你会得到一些接近你所希望的东西。
you're going to get something approximating what you were hoping for.
但这里有更深层次的东西我想让我们
But there's something deeper here that I want us to
开始发展一些本能。
begin to develop some instinct about.
首先，有没有人试图沿着这条路走下去？
First of all, did anybody try to go down this path?
这是你走过的路吗？
Is this the path that you went down anybody?
好的，所以你做到了。
Okay, so you did.
接下来会发生的是我们正在注入
What's gonna happen here is that we're pumping in
点击进入这个管道的末端，没有任何东西会丢弃事件。
the clicks into the end of this pipe and there's nothing throwing away events.
这并不是真正的采样，因为我们没有等待的东西
This isn't really sampling in the sense that the stuff that we're not waiting for
被丢弃了。
is getting thrown away.
所以，这里会排起长队
So, there's gonna be a queue inside of here that's gonna be stacking up
这些事件中有多少将会堆积起来。
how many of those events are firing is going to be stacking those up.
因此，如果您尝试这样做，如果您单击该按钮，将会发生什么情况
So ,what would happen if you tried this is if you click the button
一大堆时间，然后停止点击。
a whole bunch of times and then stopped clicking.
你将开始看到每秒一次的点击
You're gonna start just seeing the click happen once a second
因为它排出了已经堆积起来的点击队列。
as it drains out that queue of clicks that have piled up.
这并不是我们想要的采样
Which isn't really exactly what we're wanting we're wanting sampling
掉东西的地方不在那里。
which is dropping stuff isn't there.
我们看到了特定流操作的概念性问题，因为
We see the conceptual problem there with that particular stream operation because
我们可以用.zip提供的是它不会为我们丢弃东西。
what we have available to us with the .zip is it's not gonna drop stuff for us.
这不是那个特定流的定义
That's not the definition of that particular stream
手术。&gt；&gt；扬声器2：那么，
operation. &gt;&gt; Speaker 2: So,
这不像是很难观察到的
this isn't like a hard observable and
黑克斯椅&GT；&GT；凯尔·辛普森：那么，
hacks chair &gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: So,
RxJS确实有一个想法，我不想陷入所有的复杂性。
RxJS does have a notion, I didn't wanna get into all the complexities that.
它们确实有热与冷可观测的概念，并且
They do have a notion of hot versus cold observables, and
在RxJS术语中，这意味着什么，让我确保我做对了。
in RxJS terminology what that means is, let me make sure I get this right.
如果你有一个寒冷的观察者。
If you have a cold observable.
然后，除非有人在另一端观察，否则不会有任何东西进入流中
Then, nothing goes into the stream unless somebody is on the other end observing it
如果你有一个热的可观察到的。
and if you have a hot observable.
我不知道我可能会把它倒过来，但他们确实有这样的想法
I don't know I might be getting that backwards but they do have this notion of
处理这种堆积如山的事件，没有人观察它。
dealing with this piling up of events of nobody's observing it.
但在我们的特殊情况下，这实际上并不重要，因为
But in our particular case, it actually wouldn't matter because
不管你在这里看到的是热的还是冷的。
whatever whether you had a hot or a cold observable here.
你还在你的.all上观察它。
You're still observing it on your .all.
你的.zip正在观察你的观察值。
Your .zip is observing your observables.
所以，在这个特殊的情况下，它是冷的还是热的都没有关系。
So, it wouldn't matter whether it was cold or hot in this particular case.
所以，RxJS就是这样的世界。
So, there is that world in RxJS.
这是您在学习RxJS时必须学习的另一个复杂性
That's another one of those complexities you have to learn when you learn RxJS is
热观测和冷观测之间的区别。
the difference between hot and cold observables.
基本上，我试图从反应序列中去掉同样多的区别，
Basically, I tried to remove as much of that distinction from reactive sequences,
因为我发现这比好处更复杂。
because I find that to be more complex than beneficial.
但是，好的，所以这种思考事情的方式并不是真正完成我们的
But, okay, so this way of thinking about things is not really accomplishing our
总体目标是从流中丢弃东西进行采样。
overall goal of sampling with throwing things away from the stream.
我们能不能用另一种东西来手动排干溪流？
Could we set ourselves up with another thing that manually drains the stream?
就像每当这个计时器启动时，我们可以手动做梦
Like whenever this timer fires we could manually dream
排干点击流，直到有一个，然后将其推回。
drain the click stream until there was one and push it back in.
是的，我们可以去那个方向。
Yeah, we could go that direction.
我试过一次，我真的这么做了，我只是想
And I tried that one time I actually did that I just would
近似这个我就像我会排干这条小溪
approximate this I was like I'll drain the stream and
然后，不管最后一个是什么，我都会再推回去，然后。
then whatever that last one is I'll push it right back again and then.
所以这是一种方式，但这并不是真正的接受成语
So that is one way of going about it but that's not really embracing the idiom of
以你可能想要的方式进行反应式编程，好吗？
reactive programming the way you probably want to, okay?
所以，我想说的是有很多不同的方式
So, the point I'm trying to make is there's a lot of different ways
穿着这个出去。
to go out in this.
我要向你建议
I'm going to suggest to you
实现采样目标的另一种方法。
another way of approaching this that accomplishes our goal of sampling.
所以我要做的是。
So, what I'm gonna do.
我仍然会点击它，但我不会做定时器流。
I'm still gonna have a clicks of it but I'm not gonna do a timer stream.
我要做一个信息流。
I am gonna do a messages stream.
我会跟踪最新的
And I'm gonna keep track of the latest
从点击流下来的事件消息。
event message to come down the click stream.
我将在一个自由变量中跟踪它，
I'm gonna keep track of that in a free variable,
在我的闭包中的变量中。
in a variable that's in my closure.
我就叫它最新的。
I'm just gonna call it latest.
我可以把它包在它自己的外壳里，
I could wrap that up inside of its own enclosure,
就像我们在函数式编程中做的那样。
like we did in functional programming.
我可以做一个纯净的包装纸，但我在这里太懒了，我只是试着
I could make a pure wrapper around it, but I'm being lazy here, and I'm just trying
为了说明一个概念，我可以跟踪最近发生的事件。
to illustrate a concept, that I could keep track of the latest event that's happened.
所以举个例子，我可以说的是每次
So for example, what I could say is every time that
这已经发生了，我可以说最新的等于EVT。
this has happened, I can say latest is equal to EVT.
然后，在我设定的时间间隔内，
And then, inside of my set interval,
不会再推了，但是
not gonna be pushing on that anymore, but
在我设置的时间间隔内，我要做的是，无论何时触发，如果是最新的
inside of my set interval, what I'm going to do is if whenever this fires, if latest
已经设置了，也就是说，我知道队列中有一个等待单击事件。
has been set, that is, I know that there's a waiting click event in the queue.
然后，我会继续
Then, I'm going to go ahead and
推入消息队列。&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：以及
push into the messages queue. &gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: And
我只需继续并推送单击的消息。
I'll just go ahead and push the message clicked.
这样我就可以推送那个信息了
That way I actually can push that message
一起去。&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：那
along. &gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: That
部分并不是严格必需的，但它确实说明了一个事实
part's not strictly necessary, but it does illustrate the fact that I
可以在其中生成包含其他数据片段的流。
can make a stream with other pieces of data in it.
所以，我会这样做，然后我会将最新的重置为
So, I'm gonna do that, and then I'm going to reset latest back to
空。&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：这意味着
null. &gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Which means
下一次计时器触发时，如果没有发生点击，我只会继续过去。
the next time the timer fires if no click is happen I'm just gonna go on past it.
但如果有任何一直在等待的点击，我基本上会告诉它，
But if there's any click that's been waiting that I'm basically gonna tell it,
有东西在等着你，去把消息推出去吧。
there is something waiting for you go ahead and push out the message.
因此，我基本上是将布尔变量ish设置为
So, I'm basically making a boolean variable ish Into
我把它当做一条小溪。
something I'm treating as a stream.
因为在这种特殊的情况下，做布尔运算比做布尔运算更容易
Because in this particular case it's easier to do a boolean operation than it
就是做一个布尔流运算。
is to do a boolean stream operation.
有一些方法可以对布尔流操作进行建模，但它们要复杂得多。
There are ways to model boolean stream operations, but they're much more complex.
所以，我不认为你应该走这条路，因为有更简单的
So, I don't think you should go down that route when there's a simpler
选项可用。
option available.
这可能不是最完美和纯粹的反应式编程。
This isn't maybe the most perfect and pure reactive programming.
但在幕后，如果您有像RXGS和RXGS这样的反应式实用程序
But under the covers, if you have a reactive utility like RXGS and
我认为他们有一个取样的流操作。
I think they have a sampled stream operation.
他们有办法对流操作进行采样。
They have a way to sample a stream operation.
猜猜他们在做什么？
Guess what they're doing?
他们把它保存到一个变量中，所以我们只需要去掉中间商
They're saving it into a variable, so we're just cutting out the middleman and
我们自己做的。&gt；&gt；演讲者2：那时你不会黯然失色，
doing that ourself. &gt;&gt; Speaker 2: You wouldn't eclipse then,
你会吗？&gt；&gt；扬声器3：流进来，
would you? &gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Stream in,
不是吗？&gt；&gt；扬声器2：是的。
don't you? &gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Yeah.
&GT；&GT；Kyle Simpson：所以我知道，好的，是的。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: So I know, okay, yes.
所以，我的本意是，很抱歉我在这里有点偏离了轨道。
So, my intended, I'm sorry I did get a little slightly off track here.
我的本意是不要，也在这里，我试图分开关注和
My intended thing was to not, too had here I was trying to separate concerns and
然后我忘了回去做那件事。
then I forgot to go back and do that.
我的目的是观察点击的事情，并设置最新。
My intended thing was to observe the clicks thing and set latest.
所以，我打算观察Clickes事件
So, I was going to observe the clicks event and
我不想将dom事件处理与流事件处理混合在一起。
I don't want to be mixing my dom event handling with my stream event handling.
当我们想把事情分开时，这是一种混合的顾虑。
That's a mixture of concerns when we want to keep things separate.
建立这些流的全部目的是这样的
The whole purpose of setting up these streams is so
我可以在一个流中产生事件，然后在不同的地方观察它们。
that I can produce events in one stream and observe them in a different place.
在这个不同的地方，也就是我的代码第20行，我什么都不知道
In this different place which is line 20 of my code I don't know anything at all
关于点击是从哪里来的。
about where the clicks are coming from.
我不知道什么DOM元素正在处理这些，所以我希望能够
I don't know what DOM element is handling those, so I want to be able to
在很远的地方观察，所以这就是我要观察发生的事件的地方。
observe that at a far, so that's where I'm gonna observe the event happening here.
说最新的等于事件。&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：所以基本上，
And say latest is equal to event. &gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: So basically,
从概念上思考。
think conceptually.
这里有一条分界线
There is a dividing line here where
这是我们应用程序的两个完全不同的部分。
these are two entirely different parts of our application.
我们的溪流的生产和消费我们的溪流和这里。
The production of our streams and the consumption of our streams and down here.
在这些事情中，我们对DOM元素一无所知
In these things we don't know anything at all about the DOM elements
正在发生的事情。
that are occurring.